20天花130万  你就一句"我知道了"吗
$1.3 million in 20 days and you just-- you just understand?
未来可不便宜  这我们明白
The future's expensive. We knew that.
苹果每天食堂都要花掉这么多
Apple spends that daily on its in-house catering.
苹果卖的个人电脑是可以打字
Apple ships PCs that you can type on,
还有屏幕的
that have screens.
那是什么  那是个鱼缸吗
Oh, and what is-- is that a fish tank?
是  也不是
Yes and no.
你可以把它看成一个时光机
It's actually a time machine.
为了测试BIOS和硬件
See, to test the BIOS and hardware
在我们的目标速度下的运行情况
at the speed we're gunning for,
我们需要一块12.5兆赫的286we need the 12 and a half megahertz 286,
英特尔当时推出的CPU型号
但它还没有问世  我们只有8兆赫的
but it's not out yet. We only have the eight,
我们如果超频这块8兆赫的
and if we overclock the eight-- pfft--
芯片瞬间就会烧毁  这位拉里
The chip will fry in seconds, so Larry here--
是斯坦
Stan.
斯坦将芯片浸泡在矿物油中以降温
Stan's put the chip in mineral oil and cranked down the temp.
冷却使它可以在12.5兆赫运行
Cooling it makes it run at 12 and a half megahertz,
这样我们便可以在明天到来之前
so we get to design tomorrow
设计未来
before tomorrow's even here.
那怎么花了这么久
Well, what's taking so long?
计算机分销商展览时我们的原型机就能出来
We're right on track to have our prototype ready for COMDEX.
那可是在十一月
In November.
快看这个  看这个
Oh, and, hey, look at this, look at this.
三块四层的印刷电路板  这是新规范
Three four-layer PCBs. That's the new norm.
我们个人电脑的目标是12兆赫
Our PC's aiming for 12.
想象一下
So, imagine, um,
一个隐形的地铁系统  电子是列车
an invisible subway system with electrons as trains.
更多层次  更少碰撞
More layers, fewer collisions,
考虑到它是光速  真的很不可思议
which is pretty amazing when you're moving at the speed of light.
实际上电子的速度是光速的三分之一
The electrons actually move at one third the speed of light.
细节不重要  斯坦
Bigger point here, Stan,
你还是别说话了
please stop talking.
你要写的支票能实现这些创新
The checks you're writing are making innovation happen.
这难道不美妙吗
Tell me that's not beautiful,
你不感到兴奋吗
that you don't feel the excitement.
我会"感到兴奋"的
I will "feel the excitement"
等有我们商标的能运行Lotus 1-2-3的克隆电脑
when a clone with our logo encased in fancy plastic
IBM当时热销的表格软件
包装精美地摆在西尔斯的货架上
running Lotus 1-2-3 is on the shelves over at Sears
著名百货商店
而人们都争先恐后
and people are shoving each other out the way
掏钱包抢购的时候
to get to it with their wallets hanging open.
我能明白你的感受
I imagine how you must feel.
知识如此局限的人
It's difficult to believe in something
是很难产生信念
when your knowledge is so limited.
内森·卡迪夫的电话
Nathan Cardiff's on the line.
我的天呐
Mother Mary.
396毫秒
396 milliseconds.
-我的天  -别糊弄我们
- Hot damn! - Don't screw with us.
你运行没问题吗
Are you sure you ran it right?
-检查了三遍了  -戈登在哪里
- Checked it three times. - Where's Gordon?
大概还在睡觉吧
He might still be sleeping.
是的  我会回去睡觉的
Yes, I will be home for bedtimes.
我知道我昨晚也这么说
I know I said that last night,
不过今晚我保证
but tonight I promise.
注意隐私
Hey, little privacy.
396毫秒
396 milliseconds.
什么  可她还没写完呢
What? But she's not done.
她先写了硬盘查表子程序
She did the subroutine for the hard drive table lookups first.
那就是查表所需的时间
That's what the seeks clocked in at.
唐娜  我们刚刚突破了多赫蒂阈值
Donna, we just hit the Doherty Threshold.
不  我知道  我知道  我爱你
No, I know. I know. I love you.
我们突破了多赫蒂阈值
We hit the Doherty Threshold.
某人熬夜学习了
Someone's been up late studying.
在你喝着第19罐汽水嘲笑我之余
Maybe between mocking me and your 19th orange soda,
也可以稍稍表示下开心
you could register a little happiness.
我早就知道会很快
I knew it would be fast.
-你还要多久忙完  -我不知道  两天
- How much longer till you're done? - I don't know, two days?
是一昼一夜还是两个白天
A day and a night, or two full days?
31.29小时又13纳秒
31.29 hours and 13 nanoseconds.
你能不能快走  把门关上
Can you leave and shut the door?
我要召开一次动员大会
I'm calling a team-building meeting.
逗呢吧你
You're joking, right?
伙计们  都过来  都过来
All right, gather round, come closer.
今天的成就是一座里程碑
Today, we hit a milestone.
工程师衡量一台电脑的速度时
When engineers measure the speed of a PC,
常常会提到所谓的
they talk about something called
多赫蒂系统响应阈值
the "Doherty Threshold of System Response Time."
听上去很高大上  我知道
It sounds fancy, I know,
但简单说来
but, basically, what it means is
就是当你对电脑进行了一次操作
when you ask your computer to do something
敲了回车之后
and hit the enter key,
如果电脑在400毫秒以内得出了结果
if it answers you back in less than 400 milliseconds,
也就是半秒再短一点
just under half a second,
那样你就会黏在电脑前好几个小时
then you will stay glued to that machine for hours.
你可能不会一直全神贯注
Your eyes may glaze over,
但你的工作效率会狂飙突进
but your productivity will soar.
你会更加投入  甚至难舍难分
You'll be transfixed, mesmerized.
哪怕响应时间减慢到正好半秒
Even a slight deviation back to half a second response time
你的注意力也会分散
will allow your attention to stray.
你会站起身来  洗洗盘子
You'll get up and do the dishes,
拿起遥控器  看看球赛
pick up the remote, watch the game.
但只要低于400毫秒  好了
But under 400 milliseconds, ah,
一切都变得美妙了
that's the sweet spot.
你猜怎么着
Well, guess what?
我们的准卡迪夫个人电脑  尽管看上去一团乱
Our soon-to-be Cardiff PC, though it looks ragtag now,
但其测试响应时间达到396毫秒
just clocked in at 396 milliseconds.
等组装好后  我们的电脑不仅
Once assembled, it will not only
会成为市面上最快的电脑
be faster than other PCs on the market,
还会是款令人上瘾的电脑
it will also be addictive.
所以抓紧时间陪陪家人吧  各位
So spend time with your families, folks,
赶紧跟朋友喝个酒
get drinks with your friends,
因为我们电脑一上市  你们就光陪着电脑了
'cause once our PC hits, you're gonna be hanging out with it.
另外  黛比  向大家展示一下
And, hey, Debbie, let's see 'em.
这些只是我接到的电话的极小一部分
Now, this is just a smattering of the calls I'm getting now.
都是潜在的客户  分销商
Potential customers, retailers,
都迫切想知道我们的产品什么样
and they all wanna know what we're up to.
明天  《华尔街季刊》会派记者来
And tomorrow a reporter from the "Wall Street Quarterly"
报道我们的事
is coming to do a story on us.
他几乎要跪下求我了
Practically begged me to get in the door.
我们马上就要火了  各位
We're hitting the radar, people.
货真价实地火
I mean, really cooking with gas.
所以  我们或许应该
So it's only appropriate...
别别别  你这是捣乱
No, no, no, no. You'll contaminate.
-大家快跑  -乔  你要做什么
- Everybody disperse. - Joe, what are you doing?
快把那东西拿开
Get that thing outta here.
-你会毁了整件事的  -别闹了  乔
- You could blow the whole thing.  - Come on, Joe.
别紧张  谁都不用跑
Relax. No one goes anywhere.
这才叫烧书呢
Oh, that's what I call cooking the books!
意为做假账
不嘛  爸爸  我要穿粉红的
No, Daddy, my pink ones.
海莉别闹了  这袜子够粉了
Haley, stop. These are pink enough.
你的粉袜子脏了  亲爱的
Your pinks are dirty, sweetie.
苹果片配花生酱怎么样
Apple slices and peanut butter?
不要  会变成褐色
Yuck, they turn brown!
淋上柠檬汁就不会了
Not if I put lemon juice.
就穿红的吧  海莉
Just wear the red ones, Haley.
为什么妈妈说让你穿袜子
Why is it that when Mommy says, "Wear the socks,"
-你就老实穿了  -戈登
- you suddenly wear the socks? - Gordon.
好吧  宝贝  去穿鞋
All right, Smooch, go put your shoes on.
也许我们应该重新开始抽大麻
Maybe we should start smoking pot again.
那就不会焦躁了
That'd take off the edge.
是啊  我们也永远下不来床了
Yeah, and we'd never get out of bed.
你怎么这么早就听这个
How can you listen to this so early in the morning?
不会让你烦躁吗
Doesn't it get on your nerves?
2点15  别忘了
So, 2:15, don't forget.
是在操场  不在交通环岛
At the playground, not the traffic circle.
你去接孩子  带到6点
You're picking up the girls. You'll have them till 6:00.
还有这事
That's right.
-等等  你不能...  -不行
- Wait, can't you just-- - No, no, I can't.
亨特最近已经很照顾我了
Hunt's been covering for me way too much lately.
这次不能再迟交了
I can't be late with this one.
-你妈妈呢  -我都说了  他们在维加斯
- Well, what about your mom? - They're in Vegas, I told you.
萝丝得了水痘  你有听我说话吗
And Rose has the chicken pox. Do you listen?
好吧  我忘了  2点15
Fine, I blanked. 2:15 it is.
谢谢
Thank you.
记得下班赶紧回家
But please come home right after.
我还要回公司
I'm gonna have to go back to the office.
海莉把我的牙刷扔进了有尿尿的马桶
Haley threw my toothbrush in the toilet with pee pee in it.
我在做饭呢
I'm handling food here.
好吧  跟爸爸走
All right, come on.
咱们去把牙刷捞出来
Let's get the pee pee toothbrush out.
你对她做了什么  你说了什么
What did you do to her? What did you say?
戈登  别太拼命了
Gordon, hey, don't work too hard!
早
Mornin'.
我买了甜甜圈  放在休息室了
I got donuts. I put 'em in the break room.
我可不想让记者
I don't want that fancy reporter
觉得我们故意怠慢
thinking we ain't got no hospitality.
你没事吧
You all right?
我想我需要你帮忙
I think I need your help.
好的
Okay.
如果《华尔街季刊》能刊登我们的报道
Getting an article about us in the "Wall Street Quarterly,"
正面报道  能改变整个形势
the right article, that could be a game-changer,
打响个人电脑的名头  将公司领向巅峰
put our PC on the map, take this company into the stratosphere,
但如果我们看起来邋里邋遢  不可靠
but if we seem sloppy or fly-by-night,
给人留下坏印象  一切努力就付之东流了
if we project the wrong image, then it could all fall apart.
我要换上点心吗
Should I have gotten pastries instead?
不  甜甜圈挺好
No, those are fine.
我们真正的麻烦是卡梅伦
Our real problem is Cameron.
她的工作间跟猪圈似的
Her work station's a pigsty.
这很不专业  很不卫生
It's unprofessional, it's unsanitary.
坦白说  简直丢人
Frankly, it's embarrassing.
我们得在凯恩来之前把那儿收拾干净
We've gotta get it cleaned up before Kane gets here.
他约了11点
Well, he's scheduled for 11:00.
让清洁班赶紧打扫
Yeah, tell the cleaning crew to hurry.
但她不会允许他们打扫的
But she'll never let 'em.
你也知道她这个人
You know how she is.
是啊
Yeah.
你住在这附近  对吧
You live close to here, right?
对  就在伯克斯顿街
Yeah, just down on Buxton.
说服她去你那里休息一下
Then convince her to go back to your place for a break.
让她冲个澡  洗洗头
Get her to take a shower, wash her hair.
她不讨厌你  可能会听你的
She doesn't hate you and might listen.
女人之间好说话嘛
You know, woman to woman or...
你是她上司  你说不行吗
Well, you're her boss. Can't you talk to her?
穿胸罩这种事我不好跟她讲  黛比
I can't tell her to put on a bra, Debbie.
你可以
You can.
一定让她穿上
And please do.
好吧  我尽力吧
Okay. I'll do my best.
谢谢
Oh, thank you.
米莉的香肠吃够了吗
You get enough of Milly's sausage?
再吃一口
Another bite and I'd,
我就要撑炸了
hell, pop like a mosquito sucking a pig.
可还是很好吃  她真厉害
Good as ever, though. She is somethin'.
是啊  真是不错
Yep, she's a keeper.
俗话说  好佣人难找
Like they say, John, "Good help is hard to find."
谢谢你的早餐  内森
Yeah, well, thanks for breakfast, Nathan.
我得赶快回去了
I guess I'd best be getting on back to it.
回哪
To what?
什么
Beg your pardon?
你急什么
What's your rush?
乔·麦克米伦不是都安排妥当了吗
Thought Joe MacMillan had everything pretty much in hand.
你知道什么事我放不下吗
You know what I just can't shake?
露露不投资咱的个人电脑项目  我理解
Loulu not funding our PC pipe dream, that I get.
她不好应付
She's a tough one.
可是三周了还不回我电话吗
But her not returning my calls after three weeks?
-乔骂她了...  -胡扯
- Joe called that woman names-- - Bullshit.
-他不会...  -胡扯
- He wouldn't-- - Bullshit.
你怎么骂露露都可以
You could call Loulu a redneck sack of goat sperm.
只要她觉得赚钱
She'd still do business with you
还是会跟你做生意
if she thought she could make a buck.
你养成习惯了吗
Is that your new M.O.?
不管我问什么  你都说"乔"怎么怎么样
I ask a question, first thing you say is, "Joe..."?
得了  当然不是
Ah, come-- no, of course not.
老实回答我
I want a straight answer.
现在谁管事
Who's running things?
我
I am.
最好是这样  因为已经有闲话了
You better be 'cause folks are starting to talk.
说你掌控不了局面什么的
They're saying that you're letting this thing run away from ya.
谁是谁上司  给搞明白
Make clear who's working for who
不然咱俩都得成为笑柄
or else we're both gonna look like idiots.
好了  你自己认路吧
All right, I think you know your way out.
有了这块加宽的芯片载体
And with this extra-wide chip carrier,
中央处理器和协处理器
the CPU and coprocessor
可以接在同一排线里
can be clipped into a single ribbon cable.
这只是帮助我们突破多赫蒂阈值的
It's just one of the many innovations that helped us
众多创新之处之一
hit the Doherty Threshold.
你不是工程师吧
You're not an engineer, are ya?
什么
What?
你的话像是排练出来的
You just sound a bit canned, that's all.
像是别人教你的
Like you're repeating what people told you
或是你从书上看的
or getting it from books.
当然不是  我是产品经理
No, I'm the product manager.
-我有没有相关的学位...  -我的意思是
- Do I have a degree in-- - I mean,
-还多赫蒂阈值呢  得了吧  -没有
- the Doherty Threshold? Come on.  - No.
你知道有多少公司在测试时
You know how many companies think they hit that
以为自己突破阈值了吗  全部
in the testing phase? All of them.
想用散热片和机箱来搭建计算机
Try building the damn thing with the heat sink and the case.
可拿到现实中来
Once the realities of physics kick in,
就完全不一样了
it's a whole new ball game.
而且这本杂志也不是面向电脑爱好者的
Not to mention I don't write for "Hobbyists' Weekly."
读者看不了几眼就没兴趣了
My readers will be asleep in seconds.
-好吧  不是没道理  -乔
- Okay, fair enough. - Joe,
电话里我就说了  我来只是因为
I told you on the phone, I came here
纽约的马特·加里森说欠你个人情
because Matt Garrison in New York said he owed you a favor.
我又欠他个人情  所以答应过来
I owed him one, so I said I'd pop by,
但现在  我得走了
but now I gotta go.
罗恩  拜托
Ron, please, please.
和员工聊聊  听听他们的故事
Just meet some of our people, get their stories.
你绝对能写一篇在劣势中抗争的文章
There's an underdog angle here
你肯定能挖到好料的
I guarantee you'll find interesting.
-好吧  15分钟  -好
- Fine. 15 minutes. - Great.
如你所见  我们不在娱乐设施上浪费钱
As you can see, we don't waste money on amenities
你听过关于电脑程序员的那个笑话吧
because, hey, you know programmers. What's the joke?
吃披萨  生产代码的机器
"They're just machines for turning pizza into code."
好有趣
Yeah, good one.
只是这次  是个女孩  卡梅伦
But Cameron, in this case, is a girl.
很少见女孩子干这行吧
Yep, you don't see that every day.
22岁  聪明过人
22, brilliant,
写的BIOS代码颠覆世界
and writing a BIOS that defies belief.
-怎么了  -都没了
- What happened? - It's gone.
我所有的代码
All my code, I --
重启过了吗
Did you try booting it up again?
连提示符都没有
I can't even get a prompt.
没事  可能只是显示器
All right, look, it's probably just the monitor
或连接的问题  伙计们
or the connection. Guys...
怎么回事
What -- what's happening?
你有备份的  对吧
You backed it up, right?
有一点
Yeah -- yeah, at some point.
什么叫有一点
"At some point"?
这是什么
What's that?
搞什么
What the...?
你开玩笑吧  伙计们  是电涌
Are you kidding me? Guys, it was a power surge.
可能只烧坏了磁盘
Probably just burned out the disks.
你的备用盘呢
Where are your backup floppies?
软驱里有一张  烧焦了
She left one in the A-drive. It's toast.
文件分配表肯定没了
FAT's gotta be empty.
卡梅伦  其他备用盘呢
Cameron, where are the other ones?
给  都查一遍
Here, check 'em.
没东西
No.
-这张被消磁了  -这个也是  空的
- This one's degaussed. - This one, too -- wiped.
什么  怎么可能啊
What? How is that possible?
真空吸尘器
A vacuum cleaner?
你把吸尘器和我的电脑插在了一个插座里
You plugged your vacuum cleaner in my computer?!
-抱歉  -告诉我到底怎么回事
- Sorry, sorry! - Just walk me through what happened.
你...把备用盘放扬声器旁边
You put your -- you put your backups next to your speakers
然后还放歌  神哪  卡梅伦
and then you blast music? Good God, Cameron.
-你怎么不直接在盘上放块磁铁算了  -放开我
- Why didn't you just put a magnet up to them? - Get off!
镇定一点
Hey, calm down!
这人又是谁
Who the hell is this?
罗恩·凯恩  《华尔街季刊》的记者
Ron Kane, "Wall Street Quarterly."
好啦  孩子们  走啦  我们去找爸爸
Okay, girls. Let's go. Let's go see your dad.
-好吗  -爸爸  你迟到了
- Ok?  - Daddy! You're late.
费丽思老师只好打电话叫妈妈来了
Miss Ferris had to call mommy.
-抱歉  -我就要你做这么一件事
- I know. I know.  - I asked you to do one thing.
你记不住写手上行不行
You can't write it on your arm?
-不能让助理提醒你吗  -出了点意外
- You can't get an admin to remind you? - Things got crazy, okay?
我今天倒霉透了
I'm having kind of a day here.
还成了你倒霉了
Oh, you're having kind of a day?
我又有个任务要交迟了  我还保证不会呢
Now I'm gonna miss another deadline that I promised I'd make.
可是我的工作更重要啊
Well, maybe the stakes are a little bit higher in my world, okay?
-我又不是在给计算器做测试  -什么
- I'm not just QA-ing calculators. - Excuse me?
-我没...  -戈登
- I didn't--  - Gordon,
我问你
let me ask you something.
你上一次剪她们的脚趾甲是什么时候
When is the last time you cut their toenails?
你哪一个女儿对杏过敏
Or which one of your daughters is allergic to apricots?
你知道她们儿科大夫的名字吗
Do you even know their pediatrician's name?
不知道吧  因为你不必知道
No, you don't? Because you don't have to.
-是我打理好了你的生活  -妈妈  回家吧
- I make your world possible. - Mommy, let's go home.
没事了  我们...
It's okay, it's okay. We're just--
带她们走吧  戈登  我们回家再谈
just take them, Gordon. We'll talk at home.
唐娜
Donna.
-我的天  你不能带她们走  -是的
- Oh, my God, you can't. - No.
你都不能带会儿她们吗
You can't even take them.
我需要你去趟卡迪夫
I need you to come to Cardiff.
-很乱  是吧  -乱成一锅粥
- Crazy back there, huh? - Pretty sported.
我以为他们要打起来了
Thought they might come to blows.
希望我可以在这儿工作
I hope it's okay that I set up here.
你的秘书  叫什么来着
Your gal-- what's her name--
她说她觉得没问题
said she thought it would be fine.
不如你下礼拜再来吧
Look, why don't you come back next week?
我们的首席工程师说这没什么大不了的
Our head engineer just told me this whole thing's no big deal,
但就算如此  也挺让人分心的
but even so, it's kind of distracting.
我说实话吧  乔
Let me level with you, Joe.
我本来没打算写这个公司的报道
I was never gonna write a word about this company.
我认为你们能打入个人电脑市场的可能性
I think its odds of being a player in the PC market
跟给我修洗衣机的那家伙一样大
are about on par with the guys who fix my washer-dryer.
我来只是看在马特的面子上
I came only as a favor to Matt.
但是  你瞧  好心有好报
But lo and behold, the universe paid me back,
让我能见证一家太过心高气远的公司
gave me a story about a company flying too close to the sun
在IBM的阴影下毁于一旦
that burnt to a crisp in IBM's shadow.
伤痛  希望落空  梦想破灭
The pain, the dashed hopes and dreams.
写个五千字  再署个名
5,000 words on that, a byline,
我终于能离开这个烂地方
I might finally get off this crappy beat
回华尔街
and make it back to Wall Street
或者硅谷  那些值得报道的地方了
or Silicon Valley, where the real action is.
也就是说  我拿到全部素材之前
All of which is to say I'm not leaving
是不会离开这里的
till I get this in all its gory glory.
也许你没听明白
Maybe you don't understand.
我不是请你离开  罗恩
I'm not asking you, Ron.
你威胁我  好吧
Oh, a threat. Okay.
我这么说吧
Let me lob one back at you.
要是我走了
If I leave, if I go,
就只能写我看到的
I write what I got,
你我都知道那可不怎么光彩
and we both know that ain't pretty.
可我要是留下
Other hand, let me stay,
也许能报道整件事  好的和不好的都写
maybe I get the full story-- good with the bad.
卡迪夫的工程师是硅草原最好的
Cardiff's engineers are the best in the Silicon Prairie...
这可不够
That's not saying much.
他们会找到办法度过这个难关
...and they will find a way through this.
小麻烦而已  没什么大不了
It's a bump, that's all.
很好  那么你肯定愿意让我留下见识见识
Great, then I'm sure you'll want me around to see that.
不然的话  慢着  你刚刚都是胡扯吗
Or, wait, was that all bullshit?
这就是你的数据检索专家吗
This is your data retrieval expert?
你也好啊
Hello to you, too.
她的毕业论文是关于磁储存器的
She did her thesis on magnetic storage.
多久以前的事了  戈登
How long ago, Gordon?
我们要的是跟得上时代的专业技术
We need current technical know-how here.
打断一下  就好像
Oh, excuse me. Like you'd know
你就知道什么是专业技术似的
technical know-how if it hit you in the head.
你不能来这儿
Look, you can't be here.
-很好  好极了  -走吧 姑娘们
- Great, that's just great. - Come on, girls.
-女士们  走吧  -你毁了我一整天
- Ladies, come on. - You blow my whole day
结果他却让我走人吗
and he tells me I have to leave?
等等  孩子们别闹了  把着色簿拿出来
Hold up. Look, girls, calm down. Get out your coloring book.
你什么意思
What are you talking about?
他还在外面呢
With him here? Come on.
现在我们的一言一行都在放大镜下
Everything we do will be open to scrutiny.
你担心那个记者就让他走人啊
Who, the reporter? So tell him to leave.
没那么简单
It's a little more complicated.
有你在  当然什么都不简单
With you, that's a big surprise.
我这是为你考虑
I'm actually thinking about you.
如果被人发现你来这儿  就算是来帮忙
If it comes out that you're working here, even as a favor,
你在德州仪器的上司会没意见吗
you think your bosses at TI would be okay with it?
真的就为这个吗  乔
Is that it, Joe, really?
还是你不想让大家觉得
Or do you not want anyone thinking
你连自己都顾不全
you couldn't save your own...ass?
我不想要你老婆留在办公室
I don't want your wife at the office.
你到底怎么回事
What the hell's the matter with you?
没有唐娜  这事没戏的  乔
Without Donna, this thing stays dead on the table, Joe.
她是最好的人选  现在还是唯一的人选
She is our best option. Right now, she is our only option.
好吧  但对凯恩说她是卡迪夫的员工
Fine, but if Kane wants to know, she's a Cardiff employee,
别用你的真名
and don't use your real name.
我有几个问题要问你
Hey, uh, I need to ask you a couple questions.
除了留在软驱里的那张软盘
Besides the floppy you left in the A-drive
和扬声器边上那一摞
and the stack near the speakers,
你确定没在别的软盘上备份过吗
are you sure you never backed up elsewhere?
这意思是没有吗
That's a no?
好吧  那文件清单什么的呢
Okay, how about a list of files?
你有这种单子吗
Do you keep anything like that?
没有  灵感来了要忙着创作
No. When you're in the flow creating something,
谁会停下来做登记这种无用功
you don't just stop for some mindless bookkeeping.
好吧  所以才有现在的麻烦事
Right, which is why we're here right now.
你是什么人  谁的妈妈吗
Who are you, anyways? Just somebody's mother?
你有底层系统的工作经验吗
Do you have any clue what it's like to work close to the metal?
知道我失去了什么吗
Like, any idea what I've lost?
告诉你  我还是个毕业于伯克利的工程师
Well, FYI, I am also an engineer with a degree from Berkeley
我不仅编过代码
who's not only created my share of code,
-还创造出了俩大活人  -老天
- but given birth to two real humans. - Oh, God.
所以没错  我是个母亲
So yeah, I am somebody's mother
说实话  你现在这副惨相  我看也正缺个妈
and you could use one right now because, frankly, you're a mess.
别烦我了
Leave me alone.
去烧个胸罩什么的吧
Go burn a bra or something.
20世纪70年代女权主义者的呐喊
真会说  我们刚把萨莉·莱德送上了太空
That's great. Sally Ride just went to space
你把工作搞得一团糟
and here's you screwing up at work
就像小孩一样冲着想帮你的人发脾气
and lashing out like a child at the people trying to help you.
你睡了老板才得到这份工作
You slept with the boss to get here.
我总算明白为什么了
Now I know why you had to.
我现在还和他睡呢
Oh, I'm still sleeping with him,
如果你想知道的话  母夜叉
in case you're wondering, bitch.
你还真是毫无自尊啊
You really don't think much of yourself, do you?
去死吧
Go to hell.
磁盘烧了  好吧  不就是不能转了吗
It's melted, fine, so it can't spin.
反正读磁头也坏了
The read head's damaged anyway.
我们得把磁盘装到另一个转轴上
We'll have to remount it on a different spindle.
等等  那不会把另一个磁头也弄坏吗
Wait, won't that just ruin the head on that one?
是啊  你打算手动转吗
Yeah, you gonna spin it by hand?
-一次一微米  -是
- A micron at a time? - Yes.
如果宇航局的人能手工磨出
If the guys at NASA can grind parabolic mirrors
黄光六分之一波长大小的抛物柱面镜
to within one sixth of the wavelength of yellow light by hand,
我也能控制磁盘的旋转速度
I'm pretty sure I can control the rotation of a disk.
其实我的成功率比他们高144倍呢
In fact, my chances of success are greater by a factor of 144.
也许吧  但你控制不了读取
Maybe, but no way the ins and outs.
没错  所以我们要做些改进
Exactly, which is why we'll modify it.
不在磁头上用双转子马达  用步进马达
Use the stepper motor on the head, not the spinner motor.
每一转读取一次数据
Remove the data one click at a time,
再备份到第三个软驱里
back up to a third drive.
唯一的问题就是
Only problem being
就算我们等到死你也做不完
we'll die of old age before you finish.
只要文件分配表还在就不会
Not if the FAT's intact.
要是有分配表的话  除了这些烧掉的数据
That way, aside from the fried files,
我还可以通过推导重建BIOS
I can reassemble the BIOS by deduction.
我觉得她比你更能干
I think she's smarter than you are.
从遇见她那一刻起我就知道了
I knew that the moment I met her.
我本来就配不上她
How I'd never really deserve her.
说实话  她还跟着我简直让我吃惊
And, frankly, I'm amazed she puts up with me.
有人正在伤心呢
Someone's in the doghouse.
好了  我们开始吧
Come on, let's do this.
你还好吗
Hey, you all right?
我给你带了点吃的
I brought you something to eat.
走开
Just go.
很好  你可以做数据转移
Okay, you can do the transfer.
估计需要多久  艾德
ETA on that, Ed?
不会太久  已经开始了
Not too long. It's coming.
接线有点困难
Wiring's a bit tricky.
双转子马达的线就在排线的中间
Spinner wires are in the middle of the ribbon.
-妈妈  我想走了  -我饿死了
- Mommy? I wanna go. - I'm starving.
梅琳
Maylene...
抱歉  我家里还有小坏蛋等我呢
I'm sorry, I got rascals of my own at home.
-黛比呢  -乔让她回去了  我要走了
- What about Debbie? - Joe sent her home. I gotta go.
好吧
Fine.
好了  有坚果  还有葡萄干
Okay, I've got nuts and raisins.
这就是今天的晚餐吗
That's what's for dinner?
老实吃就好了  行吗
Just eat it, okay?
-非洲的孩子还挨饿呢  -戈登
- Kids in Africa are starving right now. - Gordon...
继续吧  我们得把这事做完
Com on, we need to get this done.
如果你们想专心工作  我能帮忙照顾她们
Hey, I can take them if you guys wanna keep working.
不  不用  没事的  谢谢
No, no, no. We're good, thanks.
我们不需要你再"帮忙"了
We don't need any more of your help.
好吧  你要去哪
Well, where will you be?
停车库吧  就在消防门外
Uh, the garage, I guess, just outside the fire door.
好吧  小心点就是
Fine, all right? Just be careful.
那里有一部电话  有问题就打电话
There's a phone down there. Call if you got a problem.
我们都在这个房间  好吗
Okay, and we'll be right in this room, all right?
这是能让她们不加抱怨老实吃掉的晚餐
Here, dinner, which they will eat and not gripe about.
我相信她们会乖得像小天使一样
I'm sure they'll be little angels.
好消息是  我死掉前一定会先失明
The good news is I'll go blind before I die.
至少这样我就可以停下休息了
Then at least I'll have to stop.
他们会再给你拿一台显示器来
Well, the guys are bringing you down another monitor.
好了
There.
文件分配表  基本无损
There it is, the FAT. It's mostly intact.
-感谢上帝  -别激动  这需要时间
- Thank God. - Easy, now. It's a process.
你知道你工作的样子让我想起了什么吗
You know, watching you work, you know what it reminds me of?
你总在我工作的时候打扰我吗
How often you distract me when I'm trying to work?
记得那晚在计算机课上吗
That night in CS-50, remember?
大家都离开实验室了
When everybody had left the lab
然后你就在主板组装桌上把我推倒了
and you forced yourself on me on the motherboard assembly table.
我怎么记得不是这样
I recall it a little differently.
我们花了五天时间重组弄坏的主板
It took five days to rebuild the ones that broke
因为都被你扫到地上了
when you swept them to the floor.
是你把它们扫到了地上
You swept them to the floor.
紧急激情
Hey, romantic urgency.
是啊  我记得
Yeah, I remember.
唐娜  我很抱歉
Donna, I'm-- I'm sorry.
-好了  走开吧  我要工作了  -好吧
- Okay, now leave me alone. I gotta work. - Okay.
好吧  你们想试试痒痒喷雾吗
Okay, oh, do you want tickle spray?
好啊
Sure.
有个已经不在这儿工作的人
Some guy who doesn't work here anymore
把它落在桌子上了  我就偷来了
left it in his desk, so I stole it.
有人觉得恶心  但我们就尝尝看吧
Some people think it's yucky, but let's just try it.
准备好了吗
Okay, ready?
不好吗
No?
我觉得真正的挠痒更好  你觉得呢
I think real tickles are better, what do you think?
对吧  真正的挠痒更好吧
Right? Real tickles are good.
-你才不是渣滓  -没错  你很有趣
- You're not trash. - Yeah, you're fun.
怎么了  有人我说是渣滓吗
What? Did someone say I was?
没事  姑娘们  说吧
It's okay, girls. You can tell me.
爸爸跟妈妈说  你就是"白人渣滓"
Well, Dad said to Mom that you were just like white trash.
没错  他们在开玩笑
Yeah, they were joking.
你怎么知道他们在开玩笑
How do you know they were joking?
因为他们笑着说的
'Cause they were laughing.
继续玩吧  卡梅伦
Let's go play, Cameron.
你们想看点有趣的吗
You guys wanna see something fun?
走吧  游戏时间结束  找你们父母玩去吧
Okay, go. Playtime's over. Go play with your parents.
我们快走吧
Let's go.
[驾照上有地址]
我以为乔让你离开了
I thought Joe told you to leave.
是的
Oh, he did.
但然后  我说通他了
But then we came to an understanding.
BIOS恢复得怎么样了
How's the BIOS recovery looking?
你的工程师也不愿跟我说话
Yeah, your engineers didn't want to talk to me either.
一群气冲冲的家伙
They're a prickly bunch.
我以为我一进去
I thought they were gonna try and crucify me
他们就会把我钉死呢
the moment I set foot down there.
现在你知道他们很聪明了吧
Now you know they're smart.
你肯定很不容易
Must be especially rough on you.
在这里工作了22年
I mean, 22 years here--
从卖二极管和无线电
selling diodes and ham radios...
到大型机软件  现在变成这样
to mainframe software, to this?
你觉得内疚吗
You feeling any guilt
让一个IBM的骗子
letting some IBM slickster
来把你的一切成就抢走了
come in and hijack it all away from you?
首先  查清楚
First, check your facts.
我没被任何人抢走任何东西
No one hijacked anything from me.
其次  你觉得报道
And, second, you think your little story here
我们未能如愿的希望和破碎的梦想
about our failed hopes and dreams,
能算是革命性的新闻吗
that gonna revolutionize news reportin'?
最终不过又是一堆
Hell, just another wad of paper
我用来包死鱼头的报纸
I'll wrap my dead fish heads in.
你写你的"泰坦尼克号沉没"报道吧
But you go ahead and write your Titanic story,
说我们要毁了
the one where we go down.
但我告诉你  你们都该小心点
But I tell ya, y'all should be careful.
因为等我们搭建好这台个人电脑
Because when we build this PC,
所有人都会想来插一脚
everybody gonna wanna be in
而你
and you...
你只能远远看着
are gonna be outside standing there,
一点办法也没有
your little pecker wagging in the wind.
滚出我的办公室吧  省得我揍你
Now, you get out of my office before I punch you in the face.
我们好像恢复出来了
I think we got it.
该死
Damn it!
天呐
Oh, man.
他们也把你炒了吗
They fired you, too?
天呐  那边就跟恐怖电影似的
God, it's like a frickin' horror movie over there.
别怕  我只打坏人
Hey, oh, don't worry. I only shoot bad guys.
你是来报复的  对吗
Oh, oh, you're here for payback, huh?
伸张正义
Justice!
你要写什么  就一般那些话吗
What are you gonna write? The usual, huh?
写吧  动手吧
Okay, go ahead. Do it.
他们俩真虚伪  是吧
I mean, they're both such hypocrites, right?
唐娜总是高高在上  装什么职业女性
Nose-in-the-air Donna with her whole careerwoman act,
戈登  当自己是艺术家呢  得了吧
and Gordon, the artiste? Oh, please.
就好像他和那个什么乔
Like he and Joe what's-his-face
能创造一台能跟大巨头抗衡的个人电脑似的
are ever gonna create a PC to rival the big boys.
动手啊
Do it.
我发誓  我不会说出去的
I swear to God, I won't tell.
好了
We got it.
救得漂亮  危机逆转了
Nice save. Crisis averted, huh?
很幸运  文件分配表没有丢失
Well, we're just lucky the file allocation table wasn't lost.
我找到这个后  写了一个程序
Once I found that, I was able to write a program
重新整合数据扇区
to help reassemble the data sectors.
虽然还未完全恢复
She's not completely recovered,
但据我的计算  应该恢复了93%左右
but by my calculations, about 93%.
-你是  -苏珊·费尔柴德
- And you are? - This is, um, Susan Fairchild.
她是我们的调试员
She's one of our debuggers.
多谢了  苏珊  干得好
Thanks, Susan. Nice work.
伙计们  跟罗恩讲讲你们是怎么解决问题的吧
Hey, guys. How about showing Ron here how you cracked the problem?
这问题很棘手  是吧
You really got in deep there, right?
磁盘不是烧了吗
Okay, well, the magnetic platter melted, right?
转不了了  所以我们给装到新的转轴上了
And it couldn't be spun. So we remounted it.
-你是  -戈登·克拉克  首席工程师
- And you are...? - Oh, Gordon Clark, head engineer.
拜托  IBM毁了你们的大型机生意
No, no, but, come on. IBM decimated your mainframe business.
你们大幅度裁员
You laid off scores of employees.
你有足够资源和胆识
Have you got the resources, the guts,
在个人电脑领域竞争吗
to fight in the PC world?
罗恩  我们有三点
Ron, three things--
敏捷  设想  和毫无畏惧
nimbleness, vision, and a complete lack of fear.
IBM虽然厉害  但它大而僵
IBM's formidable, but it's gotten fat.
库房根本没有地毯
The storage room has no carpeting.
都是水泥地
It's concrete.
我不了解你  但要我就用拖把  而不是吸尘器
I don't know about you, but I'd use a mop, not a vacuum cleaner.
我把清洁工开除了  但如果你想  我可以...
I had the janitor let go, but if you want, I can call--
你真是不见棺材不掉泪啊
My God, you are tenacious.
这些磁盘的确消磁了
They were degaussed, all right.
但其中一个上面是电子数据表
But one of them had a spreadsheet on it.
另一个上面是游戏的一部分
Another, part of a game.
卡梅伦的确挺马虎  但还没到这个地步
Cameron's sloppy, but she's not that sloppy.
她会用干净的磁盘做备份  而不是这种的
She would've used clean disks to back up on, not those.
这是你一手操纵的
You engineered this.
你想办法把她骗出了屋子
You got her out of the room somehow,
你制造了电涌
you made the power surge happen,
但你随便找来了几块磁盘  对不对
but you grabbed a bunch of random disks, didn't you,
把他们消了磁  然后换走了卡梅伦的磁盘
and demagnetized them all before swapping them for Cameron's?
恭喜  被你发现了
Congrats, you got me.
如果我没能恢复BIOS代码呢
And if I hadn't recovered the BIOS?
我也会在凯恩离开之前自己挽救大局
I would've saved the day myself before Kane left the building.
你做了这么多  就为了宣传
All of this for a little publicity?
别低估宣传的价值
Don't underestimate it.
他今天来的时候  对我们的工作毫不感兴趣
He came in here today with zero interest in what we were doing.
现在  不论他写什么
Now, whether he writes that
是写我们是一群即将取得重大成就的天才
we're geniuses on the cusp of something great
或是一群差点毁于一旦的局外人
or misfits who almost crashed and burned,
但至少他会做报道
at least he'll write something,
现在  我们就需要这个
and right now that's all we need.
卡梅伦呢  你还在跟她上床呢
And Cameron, who's sleeping with you?
-她只是附带损伤吗  -她会迈过这个坎的
- She's just collateral damage? - She'll get over it.
而且她今后会更小心了
Plus, she's learned to be more careful.
随便你怎么看我  唐娜
Look, you can think what you want about me, Donna.
但这也是他们的梦想  不只是我一人的
But this is their dream, too, not just mine.
我不希望他们对我的信任破碎
I'd hate to see their trust in me broken
就为了这么件有益无害的小事
over something so minor, so beneficial as this.
如果你够聪明  你显然是挺聪明的
If you're smart, and clearly you are...
就别告诉任何人  包括戈登
you won't tell anyone. Not even Gordon.
孩子们都没事  多谢关心了
The kids are fine. Thanks for asking.
你能安顿好他们吗
Hey, would you get them settled, please?
-什么  -我就来
- What? - Just-- I'll be there in a minute.
好
Okay.
你吓着我女儿了
You scared my girls.
我当时有事  抱歉
I had to leave, I'm sorry.
你是该觉得抱歉
You should be.
不知道你听没听说  我恢复了你的代码
I don't know if you heard, but I recovered your code.
没有全恢复  93.6%
Not all of it, but 93.6%.
谢谢
Thank you.
我之前对你说的话...
God, what I said to you--
算了  你当时很难过
No, forget it. You were a wreck.
而且也是情理之中
Makes sense you would be.
我还在上学的时候
One time when I was in school,
有次把可乐洒在了主板上
I spilled a whole Coke on my motherboard.
当时已经几周没做备份了
Hadn't backed up for weeks.
当时真想去跳海湾大桥
I felt like jumping off the Bay Bridge.
但我得说  我的代码
But I have to tell you, my code...
跟你的没法比
was never like yours.
你的代码
Yours is, uh...
简直像是音乐
well, it's like a piece of music.
回家吧  好好睡一觉  吃点像样的食物
You should go home. Sleep, maybe eat a real meal.
明天再干活儿
You can work tomorrow.
不  我要恢复剩下那6.4%
No, I gotta get back that 6.4%.
随你便吧
Suit yourself.
这是你的吗
Oh, are these-- are these yours?
戈登啊
Gordon.
是有点快了  是吧
Was a little fast, huh?
驾照和行驶证
License and registration?
你去够什么呢
Whoa, whoa, what are you reaching for?
只是拿驾照
Just getting my license out of the-- whoa, whoa.
你们干什么
What are you doing?
行了
All right, all right.
该死  他敢打我
Oh, shit. He hit me.
没有啊  什么
No, I-- what?
她们明天要没精神了
They're gonna be a mess tomorrow.
你是说两小时后吗
You mean in two hours?
今天真够呛
Man, what a day.
你真棒啊  真了不起
You were amazing. I mean, amazing.
苏珊·费尔柴德  我妈妈婚前的名字
Susan Fairchild? You give me my mother's maiden name?
我第一个想到的就是这个
It was the first thing I thought of.
你觉得我是我妈妈吗
So you think of me as my mother?
当然不是了
No, of course not.
别生气啊
You're being crabby.
我们都得去睡了
Come on, we both need to get to bed.
怎么
What?
怎么了
是乔烧了卡梅伦的硬盘
Joe fried Cameron's hard drive
而且弄得好像是她把备份磁盘消磁了似的
and made it look like she degaussed her backups.
他是有意的
He did it on purpose
就为了让那个记者报道你们
to try and get that reporter to write about you guys,
报道你们的个人电脑  这家公司
about your PC, about the company.
BIOS代码根本没丢
The BIOS was never lost.
他手里一直都有真正的备份磁盘
He had the real backups the whole time.
-什么  -戈登  你就跟这么个人合伙了
- What? - This is the man we've hitched our wagon to, Gordon.
你的搭档就是这种人
This is your partner in this whole thing.
但他怎么能...
But how could he? I mean--
天呐
Jesus.
他让我们那么担惊受怕
I mean, what he put us all through.
为了这么场戏浪费了我一天
Wasting my whole day on some massive fake drama?
我去找他对质时他才说出来的
He only told me when I confronted him about it.
天呐
God.
成功了吗
Well, did it work?
那个记者要报道我们了吗
Is the reporter gonna write the story
还有我们的个人电脑
about us and our PC?
怎么了
What?
怎么了嘛
我就问问
I'm just asking.
杰夫  周日还去钓鱼啊
Jeff, we still fishin' on Sunday?
汉克
Hey, Hank.
在场上看到你儿子了
Saw that boy of yours on the mound.
那小子有点诺兰·莱恩的风范啊
God, he is bringing some Nolan Ryan heat, that kid.
是啊  他们长得真快  博斯
Yep, they do grow up quick, Boz.
你要见我吗  我正在弄呢
You wanted to see me? Because I'm doing it right now.
不是为那篇报告
No, no, it's not about that report.
是这篇
It's about this one.
不仅交迟了  而且满篇错误
Not only was it late, it was full of errors.
我在马克面前丢尽了脸
I looked like an idiot in front of Mark.
对不起
I'm sorry.
你是怎么了
What's wrong?
你不是这样的人啊
You're better than this.
我是你朋友  这你知道
Now, I'm a friend. You know that.
但我不能总替你打掩护了
But I can't keep covering for you.
我还得顾及我自己的工作
I've got my own job to think about.
你现在被留用查看
As of now, you're on probation.
除非你的工作有所改进
Now, unless your work improves,
我将不得不采取行动
there may be action taken.
就这样了
That's it.
天呐
Jeez.
你这是怎么了
What the hell happened to you?
不小心  摔倒了
I got careless, fell.
昨天真悬啊
Had a close call yesterday.
是啊
Yep.
如果不是唐娜
If it hadn't been for Donna,
真是要命了呢
who knows where we'd be?
人人影视
倾情奉献
翻译
CiciXT
磁芯章鱼X
翻译
木浅薰
潇湘月影
翻译
somehacker
冬麟   ddj
翻译
如是我闻
小花豆   草总
时间轴
Kallen 芒果树叶
特效
宝宝
电脑狂人
第一季
第四集
校对&总监
草草
后期
饿得慌
顾问
大伟昔